Mr. Sebastian Robert Oliver Bird

20 Sefton Street, Leigh, Lancashire WN7 1LX
Tel: 07896 246726
Email: sebbird95@gmail.com

https://www.sebbird.com https://github.com/SebBird

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a self-taught front-end web developer with a wealth of knowledge, experience and passion surrounding HTML, CSS, React and vanilla JavaScript. I have experience utilising these skills in responsive web development projects, which can be seen on my website/GitHub.

I am currently employed for Cheshire Datasystems Ltd., where I have worked on existing enterprise-scale legacy web applications, as well as help develop completely new web-apps using React/Typescript. I am an extremely adept learner, and I am always on the lookout for ways to develop my repertoire of professional skills even further. I am also experienced in all project phases using the Agile methodology, as well as workflow management tools such as Jira and ServiceNow.

I am motivated to find a fun, challenging position with an exciting employer where I will be able to refine and expand upon my web development knowledge, and learn and participate in an active, modern development environment.

RELEVANT SKILLS:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- Typescript
- Cypress

- Git
- LESS
- AJAX/API callsResponsive Design
- Bootstrap v5.0
- Object-Orientated Programming
- jQuery
- JSP
- Adobe Photoshop
- Blender

EDUCATION

EDGE HILL UNIVERSITY: St Helens Road, Ormskirk, L39 4QP (01695 575171)

September 2019 - June 2020

Degree	Subject	Graduate Date & Classification
Masters	History & Popular Culture	December 2020 Merit

EDGE HILL UNIVERSITY: St Helens Road, Ormskirk, L39 4QP (01695 575171)

October 2016 - July 2019

Degree	Subject	Graduate Date & Classification	
Bachelor of Arts	History	July 2019 2:1	

WIGAN & LEIGH COLLEGE: Sale Way, Leigh Sports Village, Leigh WN7 4JY

September 2012 - June 2014

Level	Subject	Grade
A Level	History	В
A Level	Mathematics	В
A Level	ICT	С

BEDFORD HIGH SCHOOL: Manchester Rd, Leigh WN7 2LU September 2007 – June 2012: **10+ GCSES at grade C and above.**

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cheshire Datasystems Limited

July 2021 - Present

Junior Web Developer | Strata House, Kings Reach Rd, Stockport SK4 2HD

- Developing digital products whilst working in an Agile (Kanban) development lifecycle.
- Writing clean, efficient code using a tech stack that includes: ReactJS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSP.
- Writing code that adheres to the SOLID & DRY principles.
- Assisting in sizing requirements for a product.
- Communicating with and updating clients using tools such as ServiceNow.
- Translating UX / UI designs to dynamic websites.
- Working with other squads to share knowledge between developers in teams.
- Writing integration tests using Cypress to run through potential customer journeys, to ensure that the product created meets client requirements.
- Routinely participating in code reviews and quality assurance.
- Personally selected to be part of "Feature Squad" digital initiative, which focuses on developing, maintaining, and owning features for use across client webapps.
- Rebranded old client webapps using modern CSS & LESS.
- Working alongside projects based in ReactJS to migrate an old legacy insurance system from JSP to ReactJS.
- Creating fully automated CI/CD pipelines.

Screwfix August 2020 – July 2021

Sales Assistant | Greenbank Industrial Estate, Hindley Green

- Providing welcoming, helpful customer service in a warehouse/shopfront environment.
- Organising warehouse stock to meet company standards on safety, accessibility and presentability.
- Using in-house software to make changes or updates to stock-levels.
- Picking and dispatching customer orders in an organized, timely manner
- Taking in large deliveries, whilst ensuring the proper company policies and procedures are adhered to.
- Using equipment such as pallet trucks when required, to organize/move stock around the warehouse.
- Carrying out all of these duties in a manner which strictly adhered to government hygiene guidelines surrounding COVID-19.

Edge Hill University	October 2019 – March
Student Job Bank St Helens Road, Ormskirk	2020

Responding to and applying for various job vacancies around campus, including:

- o Data entry in an office environment
- User-testing websites and other digital platforms
- o Surveying students in a busy, public environment
- Sounding Boards
- Office administration support
- Flexible approach to vacancies and the hours needed for work
- Interacting with the general public in a friendly, approachable manner
- Ability to work as a team with a variety of people, depending on the vacancy
- Provide punctual, hard-working administration support in a busy office environment

J.D. Wetherspoons	February 2019 –
Kitchen Assistant/Bar Staff Leigh, Lancashire	October 2019

McDonald's	July 2013 – February
Crew Trainer Leigh, Lancashire	2019

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Other relevant skills, personal information:

Full Clean Driving License	Held since November 2014 and car owner
Software Package Experience	Word
	Excel
	PowerPoint
	Outlook Mail

INTERESTS

Alongside my academic interest in history, I also enjoy the practical side as I love to travel and visit other countries and learn about their respective cultures. Reading, amateur scale-modelling and trips to museums also stem from my love of history.

I also enjoy computing and ICT in general. Alongside my interest in videogaming, I have assembled computers from scratch for myself, as well as for family and friends. I have also assisted friends and family with gathering the necessary hardware to upgrade their existing computers, and have carried out small-scale repairs, all through self-taught methods.

Alongside teaching myself programming/web development, I have also explored 3D creation toolsets such as Blender and Substance Painter. My portfolio of my work can be seen here.

Physical fitness and sport also play a big role in my life as I visit my local gym regularly and enjoy playing football with my friends.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.